This plan hinges on me.
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)
この作戦は 私に懸かってる｡
(ﾌｧﾊﾞﾛ･ﾚｵｰﾈ)
たぶん あいつは竜になれない｡
She probably won't be able to transform.
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)
もう会うことはできない｡
We cannot see each other again.
What's wrong?
どうしちゃったの？
さっきは踊ってくれたのに…｡
You just danced with me!
Why don't you hand over that bracelet of yours?
左手に着けた腕輪をよこしな｡
もう 一緒に踊れないの？
Can we never dance together again?
No, never again.
ない 二度とな｡
あっ… ちょい ちょい！
速すぎるっつぅの！
Hey, hold on!
You're too fast!
What happened?!
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)何があった？
師匠～！
Master!
来るな！ 逃げろ ニーナ！
Stay back! Run, Nina!
(竜人)お前が赤い竜か？➡
So you are the red dragon?
You will die here.
ここで死んでもらう｡
(竜人)
お前 純粋な竜族ではないな？
You.
You're not pure dragonfolk, are you?
だったら なんだっていうのよ？
So what?
(竜人)東の果ての辺境に➡
I've heard of a dragon village far to the east
人と共に生きる竜族の里があると
聞いたことがある｡
where dragonfolk and humans live together.
They say that it's filled with cowards
人に媚びて生きる
臆病で誇りなき一族だとな｡
who have lost their pride,
living at the feet of humans like dogs.
くっ…｡
よせ ニーナ！ うっ！
Don't, Nina!
Favaro.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)ファバロ！
うっ…｡
What are Azazel and the others doing?
アザゼルたちは何をしている？
Bring it on, little dragon.
かかってこい 未熟な竜よ｡
I will purify your human-tainted blood.
人に汚れた貴様の血
淘汰してやる！
My mom's blood is not tainted!
お母さんの血は
汚れてなんかいない！
ドォーン！
グオォーー！
(竜人)グオォーー！
グオォーー！➡
Rage of Bahamut
They are the same
And lose themselves
Cuz there are lots of roads to go
And the path suddenly seems rougher
I wanna walk straight ahead
Knock down another dream
Most broke before they ever came true
But walk this way
Get out of my way
Depends on the way you think it
To a yielding heart
The future, hope,
Despair and worry all look all the same
So much that you'll turn down the truth
That lied to you that day
When you were prepared for it all
You go your way, don't you?
But walk this way
Get out of my way
El, step away from that demon immediately.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)エル
その悪魔から すぐに離れろ｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)エル｡
El.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)
下界は危険だ｡ 聖なる子供が➡
The surface world is dangerous.
If the humans find out the holy child is in Anatae,
王都にいると分かれば
人間たちは必ず その命を狙う｡
they will undoubtedly try to take your life.
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ･心の声)
≪聖なる子供？ このガキが？≫
Holy child?
That brat?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)アザゼル 長い間 エルを
守ってくれたこと 感謝する｡➡
Azazel, I would like to thank you
for protecting El all this time.
だが エルは返してもらうぞ｡
But I will be taking El back now.
(ｴﾙ)どうして？
Why?
≪ドォーン！
(ｴﾙ)あっ｡
ドォーン！
ニーナが…➡
Nina... She's in danger!
危ない！
-El!
-Stop!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)エル！
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)待て！
(隊長･回想)((貴様には
隊に入れるほどの価値はない))
You are not worth adding to our squad.
ドカッ！
グオォー！
ガシャン！
ニーナ嬢！
Nina!
(隊長)よくやった｡
あとは こちらで処理する｡
Well done.
We will take over from here.
Nina!
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)ニーナ嬢！
She's still just a child.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)まだ子供だぞ！
なぜ 命まで絶とうとする！
How could you take her life?
待て！ そいつを殺せば➡
Stop! If you kill her,
you'll have to answer to the king!
王が黙っちゃいねぇぜ！
へっ…｡ あんたらの王様は➡
Your king has some weird taste, you see.
変わった趣味でな
そのちんちくりんが➡
It seems he's taken quite a liking
to that little shrimp there.
えらくお気に入りのようだ｡
(隊長)勘違いをするな｡
あっ｡
Do not get the wrong idea.
This girl is nothing more than
a disposable plaything to the king.
(隊長)
王にとって このような小娘➡
使い捨ての玩具と変わらぬ｡
そんなことない！
That's not true! We danced together,
and we've even kissed!
ダンスだってしたし
キスだってした！
(隊長)最後に教えてやろう
竜の娘よ｡➡
I will tell you one last thing,
dragon girl.
The one who ordered me to kill you
私に お前の殺害を命令したのは➡
陛下だ｡
あっ…｡
was His Majesty.
てんめぇ～！
You bastard!
うわぁ～！
ドスッ！
Kill them.
(隊長)殺せ！
ふんっ！
Where did he go?
どこだ!? あっ｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)うっ！
ガシャン！
Kaisar!
カイザル！ うおっ！
ったく…｡
Damn it.
カイザル 大丈夫か？
Kaisar, you okay?
Yeah.
あばらをやられたが まだいける｡
They got me in the ribs, but I can still move.
少し鈍ったんじゃねぇか？
I think you've gotten a little rusty.
ニーナ 立てるか？
Nina, can you stand?
どうする？
どうするも何も➡
-What do we do?
-We don't have much choice.
やるっきゃねぇだろ｡
It's do or die.
グオォー！
Nina, are you okay?
ニーナ 大丈夫か？
遅ぇっつぅの｡
Where've you been?
つか なんでジャンヌが？ あっ｡
Wait, why is Jeanne here?
あれ 誰だ？
Who's that?
She appears to be a god.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)神に見えるが…｡
≪ドシン！
(竜人)グルル… グオォー！
こいつは 俺がやる｡
I will deal with him.
No, I'd like to leave here as soon as possible.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)いや
一刻も早く この場を去りたい｡
I shall handle him.
こいつは 私がやる｡
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)貴様の助けなどいらん｡
-I don't need your help.
-You've got it all wrong.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)勘違いするな｡
いらないのは お前だ｡
You're the one who's not needed.
(竜人)グオォーー！
Holy hell, that's cold!
寒っ！ うお～！
グオォ…
グオォーー…
ドドォーン！
おお～ やるじゃねぇか｡
Hey, not bad.
I could never lose to a demon
who sold his soul to the humans.
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)
人間ごときに魂を売った魔族に➡
負けることはない｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)まるで お前一人で➡
You make it sound as if
you defeated him all on your own.
倒したような言いぐさだな｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ニーナ！➡
Nina.
しっかりするんだ ニーナ！
Hold on, Nina.
Jeanne?
ジャンヌ… さん…｡
Rage of Bahamut
こいつら生かしたままで
ほんとにいいのか？
Are you sure about leaving these guys alive?
ま～た甘っちょろいことを
考えてんのかね｡
I see you're still as naive as ever.
行くぞ｡
Let's go.
In any case, our priority is
to get back to our base.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)とにかく今は
アジトに戻ることが先決だ｡
神であるあなたにも
お話ししたいことがございます｡
There are also matters I'd like to discuss with you.
手短にな｡
Keep it short.
(隊長)なぜ 陛下の邪魔をする？
Why are you hindering His Majesty?
(隊長)お前たちの行いが
正義だと言い切れるのか？
Can you truly say what you are doing is righteous?
それを見定めるため
陛下の破壊を止めるのだ｡
To find out, I must stop His Majesty's
path of destruction.
ふっ｡
何がおかしい？
What is so funny?
お前たちのやっていることは➡
What you're doing will never amount
to anything more than a tiny rebellion..
所詮
逆賊の域を超えることはない｡
ダン！
王とお前たちは 何をする気だ？
What are you and the king planning to do?
おい カイザル 早く来い！
Hey, Kaisar, hurry up.
お前たちにやれることは
何もない｡
There is nothing you can do.
Remember that.
それを覚えておけ｡
カイザル！
Kaisar. Hey, seriously, we gotta go.
おい マジで やべぇって｡
くっ！
Don't let them escape!
(兵士)逃がすな！
(兵士)こっちだ！
This way!
-Where's Nina?
-Holed up in the back.
(ﾘﾀ)ニーナは？
奥で こもってる｡
(ﾘﾀ)あのへこみっぷり➡
From the looks of her,
作戦が失敗したとか
ケガしたとかだけじゃないでしょ？
I'm guessing she's not depressed
because of some injury or the plan failing.
腕輪は 王様が死なねぇと
取れねぇ代物だった｡
Turns out the bracelet can't be removed
unless the king is dead.
だから やっちまおうとしたら
あいつが邪魔したんだ｡
So when I went to kill him, she got in my way.
(ﾘﾀ)
ニーナと王様 何かあるんでしょ？
There's something going on between Nina
and the king, isn't there?
さあな｡
Who knows?
(ﾘﾀ)
で 聖女様は まだ分かるとして➡
So, I can understand the saint,
but where in the world did you find this angel?
この天使さんは
どっから連れてきたのよ？
I am Sofiel.
私は ソフィエル｡
神界から エルを連れ戻すのと➡
I have come to these lands from the land of the gods
裏切り者を始末するために
この地へ来た｡
to bring back El and to dispose of these traitors.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)あぁ…｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ…｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)ソフィエル様｡➡
Lady Sofiel.
お尋ねしたいことがございます｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)なんだ？
There is something I'd like to ask.
What is it?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)シャリオス王が
先の戦いで使用した兵器➡
Are you familiar with the weapon
King Charioce used in the battle earlier?
あれをご存じでしょうか？
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)今より ずっと昔…
この大陸に神や悪魔が現れる➡
I have heard that it is
a magical artifact from an ancient era
その以前の時代の
魔法技術だと聞いた｡
that even predates the arrival
of angels and demons to these lands.
あっ…｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)太古より➡
A weapon of great destruction
我々 神によって封印された
魔法技術で生み出された➡
born from the ancient magical technology
the gods had sealed away.
破壊兵器｡ そう ガブリエル様は
おっしゃられた｡
That is what I was told by Lady Gabriel.
(ﾘﾀ)
どうりで すごい破壊力なわけね｡
That'd explain its power.
One of the negative legacies left behind
by the ancestors who once ruled these lands.
かつて この大陸を支配した
先人たちによる➡
負の遺産の一つであろう｡
An object even we gods were unable to unravel.
我々 神にも解明できず➡
All we could do was seal it away.
封印することしか
できなかったものだ｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)それを得るために
シャリオス王は➡
And so, King Charioce attacked
the sacred shrines in order to obtain it.
神々の神殿を襲い続けたのですね｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)なぜ 陛下は
そんな技術を使いこなせるのだ？
How is His Majesty able
to use such a technology, then?
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)
それは 我々にとっても謎だ｡➡
That is also a mystery to us.
聞きたいことというのは
それだけか？
-Is that all you wanted to ask?
-Yes.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)あっ… はい｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)では➡
Then it's time to return to the land of the gods.
神界へ戻るぞ｡
あっ｡
エル
私のそばにいることが嫌なのか？
El, do you not want to be around me?
違う そうじゃない｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)ならば…｡
No, that's not it.
Then what is it?
My power is for a higher purpose.
(ｴﾙ)僕の力は
使命を果たすためのもの｡➡
だから ここで
世界を平和にするために➡
That's why I have to stay here,
and fight to bring peace to the world.
戦わなきゃならない｡
That's why I was born!
僕は
そのために生まれてきたんだ！
あっ…｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)勘違いしてんじゃねぇ！➡
Don't get the wrong idea.
That's the reason you were born?
そのために生まれてきただぁ？
Of course that's not the reason!
そんなわけあるか バカ野郎！
あっ｡
いいか よく聞け｡
Listen up, boy.
てめぇが生まれてきた理由なんざ
一つだけだ｡➡
There's only one reason why you were born,
and it was for your mom!
母ちゃんのためだ｡➡
You were a gift from your father to your mom!
お前のおやじが 母ちゃんのために
お前を授けたんだよ！
Is there any proof of that?
それ
なんか 根拠はあるんですクワァ？
ふんっ｡
(ｴﾙ)そ… それなら➡
Then... Then why did you bring me
to the surface world?
なんで僕を下界に連れてきたの!?
That just sort of happened!
それは偶然だ！
はっ…｡
分かった 神界に戻る｡
エル｡
Okay, I'll return to the land of the gods with you.
El.
(ｴﾙ)ごめんね お母さん｡
I'm sorry, Mother.
また 適当なこと言って…｡
There you go running your mouth again.
Don't be surprised if this comes back to bite you.
知りませんよ
あとで面倒なことになっても｡➡
クワッ！
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)て… 適当じゃねぇよ➡
I know what I'm doing, idiot!
バカ野郎！
≫(ｴﾙ)ソフィエル？➡
Sofiel?
Sofiel.
≫ソフィエル｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)えっ？
Can we return to the land of the gods tomorrow?
(ｴﾙ)
神界に戻るのは明日でもいい？
I want to say a proper goodbye.
ちゃんと お別れしたいんだ｡
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)ああ｡
(ｴﾙ)ありがとう｡
Okay.
Thank you.
((ない 二度とな))
No, never again.
The one who ordered me to kill you
(隊長)((私に
お前の殺害を命令したのは…))
was His Majesty.
(隊長)((陛下だ))
ふざけんな…｡
Screw this.
ふざけんな！
Screw this!
うぅ… 殺害ってなんだよ！
What do you mean, he wants to kill me?
That lying jerk!
うそつき野郎～！
Nina?
ニーナ？
はっ…｡
What's going on, Mugaro?
どうしたの？ ムガロちゃん｡
なんか用？
You need something?
I'm going to return to the land of the gods.
僕 神の国に戻るね｡
そっか｡ ジャンヌさん 喜ぶね｡
Oh, I see.
I bet Jeanne is happy.
じゃあ 今日はムガロちゃんと一緒に
馬車で寝よっかな～｡
Well, then maybe I'll sleep
in the carriage with you tonight.
えっ いいの？
成長しちゃってるよ？
Really?
I've grown since then.
It's fine. Come on, let's go.
いいよ｡ 行こう 行こう｡
(ｴﾙ)あっ あっ…｡
ニーナ 大丈夫？
Nina, are you okay?
What do you mean?
何が？
あっ…｡
なんでもない｡
変なムガロちゃん｡ ふふっ｡
Never mind.
You're so weird, Mugaro.
(ｴﾙ)ははっ… そうかな？
そんなに変じゃないよ｡
-Am I? I'm not weird at all.
-You totally are.
ほら 行くよ～
変なムガロちゃん！
Come on.
遅い｡ 何をしていた？
You're late. Where have you been?
(隊長)申し訳ありません｡
My apologies.
エイボスへ発つ｡
留守の間 城を任せる｡
I am leaving for Eibos.
I leave the castle in your hands while I am gone.
いよいよですか｡
ああ｡ はざまの封印を解く｡
Has the time finally come?
Yes, I will break the rift open.
(隊長)すぐに準備を始めます｡
I shall begin preparing right away.
昨晩 赤い竜を処理しました｡
We disposed of the red dragon last night.
そうか｡
I see.
昨日の侵入者
結局 捕まらなかったってな｡
I heard they never caught
those trespassers from last night.
まだ王宮内に
いるってことはないよな？
There's no way they're still in the palace, right?
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)
アレサンドを見なかったか？
Have you seen Alessand?
(兵士)
いえ ここでは見ていません｡
No sir. He has not been here, sir.
そうか｡
I see.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)共に戦えずに すまんな｡
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)いえ｡➡
I am sorry I cannot stay and fight with you.
No, you can leave this to us.
こちらのことは お任せください｡
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)頼んだぞ カイザル隊長｡
I'm counting on you, Captain Kaisar.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)
今は ただの脱獄犯ですよ ははっ｡
I'm just an escaped prisoner now.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)ははっ はははっ｡
Will you come back to the land of the gods as well?
お前たちも神界に戻るか？
い… いや 自分は大丈夫っす｡
No, we'll be okay.
んん…｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)も… 戻ったところで➡
Even if we returned, the best-case scenario
is that we'd be imprisoned,
よくて禁固… 最悪➡
worst-case scenario, we'll be officially banished.
神界追放を宣告されますよね？
それは 私も同じだ｡
That goes for me as well.
ガブリエル様の許可なく
下界へ降りてしまったからな｡
I came down to the surface world
without Lady Gabriel's permission.
はあ～!? 何してんだ お前！
What? What were you thinking?
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)
お前にだけは言われたくない！
You're the last person I want to hear that from.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)は… はい｡
I'm sorry.
だが 少し➡
But I think I finally understand
where you are coming from.
お前の気持ちが分かった気がする｡
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワッ？
What now?
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)はい？
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)お前たちは下界へ残れ｡➡
You should stay here on the surface world
そして この者たちと
王の真意を測るのだ｡
and help these people discover
the king's true intentions.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)お… 俺に
命令するんじゃねぇ！ バカ野郎｡
Don't order me around, idiot!
ニーナ 大丈夫か？
あっ ジャンヌさん➡
Nina, are you okay?
Jeanne.
元気でね｡
あ… ああ｡➡
Take care.
We will see each other again.
必ず また会おう｡
うん 絶対｡
Yup. Definitely.
By the way, where's Mugaro?
そういえば ムガロちゃんは？
アザゼルのところだろう｡
Probably with Azazel.
Mugaro.
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ムガロ｡
ムガロという名を覚えていてくれ｡
Remember the name Mugaro.
Yup.
Now go on.
もう行け｡
(ｴﾙ)ありがとう アザゼル｡
Thank you, Azazel.
As horrible as you are
I can't help but love you
Even while I waited
That is all I felt
Ephemeral lovers, both flawed and missing pieces
We have finally become one
In this miniature garden at the edge of sorrow
Can you hear my heart speaking?
Ah, I may no longer feel
That I want to go back in time
But there are feelings, feelings, feelings
I can only feel now
I want to run away with you, dancing
Just like in a fairy tale
Don't tell me it will only be this once, darling
I am on the same ark
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Yeah
Cinderella step
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Yeah
Cinderella step
あの…｡
ドスッ！
ごめんな｡
(ｴﾙ)えっ…｡
I'm sorry about this.
Kaisar's morning starts slightly late.
How late?
What could he be pondering about?
What are you pondering about?
-Next time.
-No answer?
Next time on Rage of Bahamut:
Virgin Soul, "Vengeance."
-First, we must eat some meat.
-You like the meat too?!
Baha Baha Baha Soul!
Please watch next time too.